<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.9.9" created="2019-02-18 22:35" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Brown Daily Herald</title>
	<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com</link>
	<description>Serving the community daily since 1891</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 22:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://www.browndailyherald.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://www.browndailyherald.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2518</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[chrisschutte]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[crhisschu@shu.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Chris Schutte]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Chris]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Schutte]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2539</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[Eric Choi]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[eric@choi.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Eric Choi]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Eric]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Choi]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2375</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[miapattillo]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[mia@pattillo.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Mia Pattillo]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Mia]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Pattillo]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

	<wp:category>
		<wp:term_id>7</wp:term_id>
		<wp:category_nicename><![CDATA[features]]></wp:category_nicename>
		<wp:category_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:category_parent>
		<wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Features]]></wp:cat_name>
	</wp:category>

	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/cropped-12371152_10153412077540958_8076506182949228397_o-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Brown Daily Herald</title>
	<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 

	<item>
		<title>The college effect</title>
		<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com/2018/05/25/the-college-effect/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 04:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[chrisschutte]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.browndailyherald.com/?p=2830787</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[As throngs of students coming from pre-games and “darties” swarmed the Main Green for Spring Weekend, another group was avoiding the muddy mess altogether. At the W. Alton Jones Camp in West Greenwich, around 70 substance-free students went hiking, played sports and even found some time for homework.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>

Though events like Spring Weekend and Halloween may make substance use feel prevalent on campus, around 20 percent of students identify as substance-free, according to Tanya Purdy, the director of BWell Health Promotion. But according to The Herald’s Fall 2017 <a href="http://www.browndailyherald.com/2017/11/26/herald-fall-2017-poll-results-methodology/">undergraduate poll</a>, the number might be closer to 8 percent.

That poll found that four in five Brown students drink alcohol, whereas a 2014<a href="https://pubs.niaaa.nih.gov/publications/CollegeFactSheet/Collegefactsheet.pdf"> national survey</a> found just three in five college students do. The pressures to drink or use drugs can shift over students’ time at Brown, pushing them toward communities of people who share their values.

[infogram id="097aedba-bf53-407b-83ef-ee0d842b3bd5" prefix="Gco" format="interactive" title="Fall 2017 Herald Poll Substance Use"]

Within these disparate friend groups, certain on-campus groups provide a college experience removed from the substance use that is typical to Brown. Founded this year, the club “SoBear” <a href="http://www.browndailyherald.com/2018/02/06/substance-free-students-carve-niche-social-scene/">has become a refuge</a> for substance-free students on Brown’s campus.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>

“Most clubs I found, if there wasn’t substance use happening at the clubs, kids were talking about it,” said AJ Davis ’20, the president and founder of SoBear. Davis spent his time with friends he had made in his substance-free housing, often heading off campus on weekends “because (campus) was a bit toxic.”<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>He founded SoBear to create a strong community of sub-free students by hosting events like the Spring Weekend camping retreat.

Sub-free communities exist beyond SoBear, too. This year, the University gave students the opportunity to live in <a href="http://www.browndailyherald.com/2017/04/19/university-provides-new-housing-option-substance-free-students/">Donovan House</a>, a substance free program house located in the former Plantations House.

“The house itself fosters a community for students who are sub-free (and whose) sub-free identity is very important to them to the point where it affects how they want to live,” said Kiana Phillips ’19, a residential assistant in Donovan House.

While these groups help sub-free students connect with each other, freshmen new to Brown are often left searching for friends that hold similar interests and values.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>

“I have seen the aftermath of someone who has had too much alcohol and gone beyond their limits,” said Poom Pipatjarasgit ’21, a sub-free student. “It does sometimes get lonely on weekend nights.”

While freshmen can be lost in the mix, older sub-free students can attest that the pressure of using substances<a href="http://www.browndailyherald.com/2013/04/17/white-older-students-more-likely-to-use-substances/"> fades over the years</a> of attending the University.

“As you get older and spend more time here, you solidify your friend groups,” Davis said, echoing the experiences of other sub-free students who became more comfortable throughout their time at Brown. “You know how to navigate those situations better.”

Freshmen feel the most pressure to overuse substances. To combat this, BWell ensures that all first-years receive alcohol training, Purdy said.

Many students try substances for the first time at college. Those who did drink or use drugs in high school are more likely to do so in college, according to Angelo DiBello, assistant professor of behavioral and social sciences.

Health Services sees binge drinking rates increase during a student’s first semester, especially the first six weeks, a phenomenon Purdy referred to as “The College Effect.”

“We try to be careful and provide really intentional education during that time,” she added.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>

Manny Dallas ’18, said that he spent more time drinking during his first two years, when it felt more “novel then than it is now.”

“Your freshman year, you’re not cemented in these friendships … (and) there is an element of wanting to feel comfortable with people you don’t know so well,” he added. “As you mature, you’re more comfortable being sober with people you don’t know.”

[caption id="" align="alignright" width="295"][media-credit id=1852 align="alignright" width="295"]<img class=" wp-image-2807136" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Lowentheil_Drugs-Alcohol_JillianLanney-195x300.png" alt="" width="295" height="453" />[/media-credit] The Herald's Spring 2013 Poll also found that older students were more likely to use substances.[/caption]“There’s definitely a unique American college culture, which is not unique to Brown in any way, that makes that high-risk drinking seem more appealing and make it look like more people are doing it,” DiBello said. Societal norms influence drinking behavior more than gender or participation in Greek life, he noted.

Within its educational initiatives, the University attempts to encourage safe drinking rather than cracking down on drinking entirely. Students can use substances in a healthy way, Purdy said. Brown’s rates of substance use align with peer institutions and New England in general, which sees higher rates of alcohol and marijuana use compared to the rest of the United States.

Henry, a senior who asked only to be identified by his first name because he feared professional repercussions, had little experience with drinking before he arrived at Brown, yet he quickly found himself immersed in nightly parties full of new people. At one of these parties, Henry had his first real drink.

But Henry found that parties are not a necessity when it comes to social life. “You meet people when you go out, but you don’t necessarily get to know somebody,” Henry said.

As students’ time at Brown goes by, some may feel that they outgrow substance use. One student, granted anonymity by The Herald because he feared professional repercussions, began smoking marijuana in high school. He started dealing drugs during his sophomore year of college for income and to supplement his own drug use. But after his grades suffered, the student decided to stop dealing and even began using less to focus on his schoolwork.

After four years at Brown, Henry ultimately feels nonchalant towards substance use. “If you do it responsibly and you’re not getting into patterns of clear abuse … alcohol and drugs can find a role in your life that helps you keep a balance,” he said.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>

Once Henry made friends, any pressure to drink disappeared. “Over time you realize that you don’t need to,” Henry said. “There’s much less of that (pressure) once you start making friends and having a group where you’re comfortably able to have a more quiet weekend.”]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2830787</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-05-25 00:04:57]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-05-25 04:04:57]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[the-college-effect]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-chrisschutte"><![CDATA[chrisschutte]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-alex-smolar"><![CDATA[Alex Smolar]]></category>
		<category domain="series" nicename="commencement-magazine-2018"><![CDATA[Commencement Magazine 2018]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="features"><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="university-news"><![CDATA[University News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_spost_short_title]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_is_featured]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_embed_code]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[bdh_reporter_type]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Senior Staff Writers]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[substance-free]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[substance-free]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Though events like Spring Weekend and Halloween may make substance use feel prevalent on campus, around 20 percent of students identify as substance-free.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[77]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kia_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Substance use by students increases with time spent at college, but sober communities exist]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dsq_thread_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[6691158620]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_series_part_5433]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>An oral history of student activism since the 1980s</title>
		<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com/2018/06/01/oral-history-student-activism-since-1980s/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 04:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Choi]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.browndailyherald.com/?p=2830855</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<dl id="" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px;">
 	<dt class="wp-caption-dt"><img class="size-large wp-image-2830884" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/herald-students-fast-1024x678.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="430" /><span class="mceMediaCreditTemp mceNonEditable" data-media-credit-id="" data-media-credit-name="Herald Archives" data-media-credit-align="aligncenter">Herald Archives</span></dt>
 	<dd class="wp-caption-dd">Students begin fasting to protest apartheid.</dd>
</dl>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">RONALD REAGAN (1981-1989)</span></h2>
<em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having grown up in the midst of the Vietnam War and the peak of distrust in government, students during the 80s were highly skeptical of the government, protesting CIA recruitment, University investment in South Africa, and the nuclear arms race.</span></em>
<table style="width: 100%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Jeremy Varon ’89</strong></td>
<td>“We are the children of Watergate. There had been this horrible usurpation of power by this monster, Nixon, and there had been the most horrible war, Vietnam. The liberal establishment was reestablished, and then the message for a lot of us, for liberal households, was, ‘Order has been restored. America is America again.’ And then Reagan gets elected, and this falls like a hammer. Everything we were taught to believe about America seemed in crisis — standing up for the underdog, commitment to social equity, that peace is preferable to war. It felt like a call to action — very much like Trump, but I think people weren’t so stunned and paralyzed and overwhelmed with rage and shock that it was easier to enter into activism.”</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Andrew Meyer ’89</strong></td>
<td>“We didn’t know it at the time, but those were the final years of the Cold War. And so it was a superheated geopolitical situation. People had this feeling that we were reliving through a sea change in the politics of the country. A lot of our forebears, a lot of the generation of the 60s and the early 70s, they were feeling like we were living through an era of reaction — like a lot of the progress they had made was being undone.”</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Todd Weir ’88</strong></td>
<td>“I was always nostalgic for the 60s. I always felt like the 60s were the time when one should have really been a student. In retrospect, I think we were still living in the aftermath of that political culture. I think there were a lot of continuities, actually, in the way we went about stuff and how we thought.”</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Jason Salzman ’86,</strong> <em>suicide pill campaign</em></td>
<td>“Those of us who admired the 60s were thinking, ‘Shit, if only we had been at Brown in the 60s.’ The activism is always greener.”</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"> - </span>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">ANTI-APARTHEID MOVEMENT</span></h3>
<img class="size-large wp-image-2830856" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Protest005-1024x724.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="460" />

Students demanded that the University divest from South Africa. Above, Marie Testa '86 presents a list of demands to the Corporation.
<table style="width: 100%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Colette Matzzie ’88.5</strong></td>
<td>“Saying Brown should divest — it was such a new concept. The idea that you would take what are usually just sort of these conservative investments made on the basis of return only and say, ‘How does Brown’s money support a dictatorship?’”</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">SHANTY-TOWNS</span></h3>
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="650"][media-credit name="University Archives" align="aligncenter" width="650"]<img class="size-large wp-image-2830893" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-31-at-11.04.33-PM-1019x1024.png" alt="" width="650" height="653" />[/media-credit] Students construct Shantytowns on the Main Green to protest the University's investment in companies doing business in South Africa.[/caption]
<table style="width: 100%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Maria Testa ’86</strong></td>
<td>“It was an illustration really, a constant reminder that these are the conditions of people living in South Africa, that we are, with our money, with our U.S. money, with our Brown University money, supporting the regime that allows people to live in conditions like this. That was considered to be the symbolic movement across the country, that we are going to soil our beautiful campuses with shanty towns.”</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="650"][media-credit name="Herald Archives" align="aligncenter" width="650"]<img class="size-large wp-image-2830885" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-31-at-1.54.06-PM-1024x738.png" alt="" width="650" height="468" />[/media-credit] Students end fast protesting apartheid on 10th day.[/caption]
<table style="width: 100%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Paul Zimmerman ’88</strong></td>
<td>“We were not successful in the short-term, immediate goal of getting Brown to divest, but I think in the benefit of hindsight, we were absolutely successful — the student movement, the general anti-Apartheid movement — in changing public opinion. Within a year, Congress passed the comprehensive anti-Apartheid sanctions act, which had a huge impact. And then within a number of years thereafter, Nelson Mandela was released. The country was completely transformed. Now, did my fast do all that? Of course not. But were people like me doing their part all around the country and, frankly, all around the world? Did that contribute to international pressure? I really believe that the answer to that question is, yes, it did.”</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">CIA RECRUITMENT</span></h3>
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="650"][media-credit name="Herald Archives" align="aligncenter" width="650"]<img class="size-large wp-image-2830862" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/IMG_2184-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="488" />[/media-credit] October 31, 1983. "Brown Students Demonstrate Against Invasion of Granada."[/caption]
<table style="width: 100%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Jeremy Varon ’89</strong></td>
<td>“This is a local struggle on a single campus that, in our minds, was deeply connected to a larger post-Vietnam anti-intervention politics.”</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">SUICIDE PILLS</span></h3>
<table style="width: 100%;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Jason Salzman ’86</strong></td>
<td>“The vast majority who voted for it did not really want suicide pills. I think a lot of students learned a lot about the issue as a result of the referendum. The suicide pills … they were symbolic, but it was also a real proposal. Having suicide pills, in my mind, couldn’t hurt. I didn’t see any danger to them, they’d be locked up, and in the meantime their presence would be sending a message about how serious the situation was.”</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">GEORGE H.W. BUSH (1989-1993)</span></h2>
<em>The University became the subject of student criticism, sometimes more than national issues.</em>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Naomi Sachs ’92</strong></td>
<td>“What I was more active in seemed a little bit more close to home. It may be that just personally I felt like I needed something that I could get my head around or feel like I could do something about. For me, global politics just seemed too big and too unwieldy and impossible to have a significant impact. Before Brown, I was concerned about human rights, and I was concerned about nuclear holocaust, which seemed like a real threat at that time. Those are what I gravitated to first. And then once I got to know the various other options and once I felt more personally affected by the sexual assault issues and LGBT issues, then it became more personal.”</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Nerissa Wu ’89</strong></td>
<td>“I personally moved on to more women’s issues and environmental issues and local social justice issues. Providence at the time — there were pockets of very poor areas of the city. It just seemed like there were different impacts we could have on more local issues because of personal action.”</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">RAPE LIST</span></h3>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Naomi Sachs ’92</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There were a couple years where this issue of sexual assault on campus was very widespread. And it wasn’t just at Brown, but Brown was one of the main universities in the country that was getting a lot of coverage. It was hard to be a student there and not be touched by it in some way.”</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">NEED-BLIND TAKEOVER OF UNIVERSITY HALL</span></h3>
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="650"][media-credit name="University Archives" align="aligncenter" width="650"]<img class="size-large wp-image-2830860" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Protest001-1024x724.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="460" />[/media-credit] Students occupy University Hall in 1992 to protest the University's financial aid policies.[/caption]
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Naomi Sachs ’92</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I was drawn to that (the need-blind sit-in) because it seemed more practical. The students against nuclear suicide was away to speak out against something, but pretending to die in front of the building where the CIA was recruiting didn’t feel like it was having … a measurable impact whereas doing a sit-in and actually carrying on a discussion with the administration for changes in Brown’s policies, that felt more productive.”</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
&nbsp;
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">BILL CLINTON (1993-2001)</span></h2>
<em>Many students felt that America had returned to what it truly was upon Bill Clinton's election.</em>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><b>Gregory Cooper '01</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This was before 9/11, we had a budget surplus … There wasn’t the same sense of urgency with respect to our politics that I think people feel today.”</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">
GEORGE W. BUSH (2001-2009)</span></h2>
[media-credit id=2083 align="aligncenter" width="650"]<img class="size-large wp-image-2830913" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/March-6-2003-1024x671.png" alt="" width="650" height="426" />[/media-credit]<i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Students were put off by the political process, turning often to activism instead. The Bush Era saw frequent protests of the Iraq war.</span></i>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Joshua Segall ’01,</strong> protested the 2000 presidential election</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was sort of obvious that this kind of messed up ballot had prevented Gore from being president. We had a sense that the election would be consequential. I don’t think we knew how consequential it would be.”</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">BARACK OBAMA (2009-2017)</span></h2>
[media-credit id=2063 align="aligncenter" width="600"]<img class="size-full wp-image-2830914" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/talerico_refugee.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="400" />[/media-credit]
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong> Krissia Perla ’15 MD ’21 </strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Generally, people were more complacent with the administration at the time.”  </span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">FOSSIL FUEL DIVESTMENT</span></h3>
[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="584"][media-credit id=1964 align="aligncenter" width="584"]<img class=" wp-image-2813145" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/kerman_divestcoal_narayen1.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" />[/media-credit] Fossil Free Brown joined 400 other campuses nationally and internationally in promoting divestment from top fossil fuel companies. The group, which used to be the Brown Divest Coal Campaign, embraces broader goals after the Corporation decided not to divest from coal.[/caption]
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Emily Kirkland ’13</strong>, Brown Divest Coal</span> </strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">"</span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Often you have campaigns targeting the university because that's a way for students to use the power that they have. I learned through working on Fossil fuel divestment was that it's not about making the case. It's about building enough power that you don't give the administration a choice. You have to put them in a position where they have to negotiate with the campaign because they are never going to make concessions just because you present them with enough information or because you are convincing.” </span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">DONALD TRUMP (2017- )</span></h2>
<em>The Trump Era has <a href="http://www.browndailyherald.com/2017/05/16/wake-november-8/">thus far</a> seen students come together with Providence community members to protest the administration's sweeping changes, such as the travel ban and the end to DACA. </em>

[media-credit name="Jasmine Ruiz" align="aligncenter" width="636"]<img class=" wp-image-2826735" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Sundar_Congressmen-DACA_JasmineRuiz-2.jpg" alt="" width="636" height="424" />[/media-credit]
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Emma Galvin ’18,</strong> Student Labor Alliance Organizer</span></strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There are bigger fires to put out right now than the stuff internal to the campus. It feels like Trump's election sort of demoralized energy. People were really overwhelmed and a little more scattered."</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">APATHY IN ACTIVISM</span></h2>
[media-credit name="University Archives" align="aligncenter" width="650"]<img class="size-large wp-image-2830859" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Protest002-1024x724.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="460" />[/media-credit]<i><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Brown is frequently recognized for its activism in the news, sometimes just a small minority of students working for change can give the impression of an entirely activist campus.</span></i>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Todd Weir ’88,</strong> protested CIA recruitment</span></strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was a very intense subculture at the University. The climate, in a way, was excellent because we were a group of people who considered ourselves radical and enjoyed each other’s company. There was a kind of disappointment that we were just a minority, but in retrospect that’s sort of obvious that that was all we were ever going to be.”</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>David Goldsmith ’88.5,</strong> protested Reagan’s foreign policy</span></strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There’s a strident core, there’s sympathizers, … there’s the administration, which always tends to be differently sympathetic but a little more tempered, middle of the road … I feel like it was how it’s always been, always will be.”</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Jason Salzman ’86,</strong> protested the nuclear arms race</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As an activist, the climate always seems less active than you want. You’re always wanting more from students. It was a fairly apathetic time, which doesn’t mean there weren’t plenty of students who cared and were involved — but the vast majority were not.”</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Daniel Sherrell ’13.5,</strong> Brown Divest Coal</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">"I met very few truly apathetic people. I just think that not everyone knew where to look to get active on a issue"</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Emma Galvin ’18.5,</strong> Student Labor Alliance</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“People will be super down to put on the mask and march in University Hall — and I'm all for it — but I think that there also needs to be relationship-building that happens." </span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Scott Warren ’09,</strong> protested Darfur genocide</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Every generation thinks that they were more active than the newest generation. The reality is that young people are really active. They just take action in different ways."</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2></h2>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">PUBLICITY &amp; THEATRICS</span></h2>
[media-credit id=1822 align="aligncenter" width="475"]<img class=" wp-image-2830909 alignleft" src="http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/4-23-1992_Needblind_Protests-576x1024.png" alt="" width="475" height="844" />[/media-credit]
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Colette Matzzie ’88.5</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There was no such thing as social media. There was no way to get your voice heard online — there was no such thing. So pulling people together in a rally, signing petitions, having a hunger strike in Manning Chapel, which got national press — was the way.”</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Todd Weir ’88</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There’s a very theatrical element to protesting. It’s meant for public consumption, it’s meant to be in the newspapers, it’s meant to be on television if possible. It often had this gimmicky element to it.”</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>John Crouch ’91.5</strong>, ACLU student organizer</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I didn’t believe in civil disobedience, when you’re disobeying laws that are otherwise just that you don’t think are unfair or unconstitutional, like blocking streets so people can’t get to work, blocking people from getting to class or from hearing speakers who they want to go see. There were always tensions when those of us from the ACLU were working with larger groups from the hard left. We were occasionally working for the same things, but we were there for different reasons.” </span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Maria Testa ’86, </strong>anti-apartheid movement</td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“To be taken seriously, you need to be at the table, but without the protests and the groundswell, I don’t think we would have gotten to the table.”</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Jeremy Varon ’89</strong></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They knew who they were admitting. They knew it was a bunch of curious, crazy, precocious rebels. At some level, they were welcoming all the grief that we gave them, and at some level I have to give the institution credit for subjecting themselves to that kind of moral scrutiny. That’s the sense in which my activism feels like a legacy of Brown and not just a legacy of protesting Brown.”</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2830855</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-06-01 00:55:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-06-01 04:55:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[oral-history-student-activism-since-1980s]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-eric-choi"><![CDATA[Eric Choi]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-jacob-lockwood"><![CDATA[Jacob Lockwood]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-lydia-defusto"><![CDATA[Lydia DeFusto]]></category>
		<category domain="series" nicename="commencement-magazine-2018"><![CDATA[Commencement Magazine 2018]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="features"><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2083]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_spost_short_title]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[70]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_is_featured]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_embed_code]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[bdh_reporter_type]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[SENIOR STAFF WRITERS]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[custom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[single-feature-photo-with-gallery.php]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw_text_input]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[student activism]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_focuskw]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[student activism]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_linkdex]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[67]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dsq_thread_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[6704104253]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_series_part_5433]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>University program teaches ASL, Deaf culture, history</title>
		<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com/2019/01/24/u-program-teaches-asl-deaf-culture-history/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 05:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[miapattillo]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.browndailyherald.com/?p=2833178</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">As students in the University’s American Sign Language program enter their classroom, they immediately fall silent. The mode of communication shifts from vocal chords and shaped lips to hand gestures and emotive expressions. In this classroom, professors encourage full immersion not only to learn a new language, but also to be inclusive of everyone regardless of their hearing status. ASL is what connects the students, creating an intimate but powerful community.</p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">The ASL program at Brown consists of level 100-500 classes and is taught by Lecturer in American Sign Language Tim Riker and Visiting Lecturer in American Sign Language Heather Nowicki, both of whom are Deaf. Though it initially did not offer course credit, the program eventually hired a full-time faculty member and created a series of courses for credit in 2005, Riker said. Today, the program is among the top 10 languages taught at the University, with around 70 students enrolling this fall semester, roughly the same number of language students in the Italian or Korean programs, Riker added. After the last class in the program, SIGN 0500: “American Sign Language V,” students who hope to continue studying ASL may pursue an independent study or, with enough student interest, SIGN 0600. </span>There are currently no Deaf students in the ASL program.</p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">“People come out of (the ASL program) at an incredibly conversational, if not fluent, level,” said Siena Rafter ’20, a teaching assistant for the introduction level courses. “It’s a testament to how brilliant Tim is in teaching this course.”</span></p>
<p class="p2">Some students in ASL courses have friends or family members who are Deaf, while others just have a general interest in the language, Riker said.</p>
<p class="p2">The courses entail not only a study of the language, but of the culture and history of the Deaf community as well, which many students cited as one of the most enriching aspects.</p>
<p class="p2">“The language doesn’t exist on its own — there’s a whole culture of the people who use the language and it’s important that we learn about and get exposure to that as well,” said Claire Kim-Narita ’21, who has been taking ASL for three semesters.</p>
<p class="p2">“A lot of people sort of forget about the Deaf experience,” said Zoe Fieldsteel ’15. “It’s helpful to have in the back of your mind that this is a level of human diversity to be aware of.”</p>
<p class="p2">Fieldsteel entered the ASL program on a whim as a linguistics concentrator seeking a new language experience. Today, she teaches high school math at the Learning Center for the Deaf in Massachusetts.</p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">“I think about when I first came to Brown and the people I wouldn’t have been able to communicate with years ago — my friends, the kids in my classroom. That’s wild,” Fieldsteel said. “Those classes centered my career, and I had no idea it would lead me here.”</span></p>
<p class="p2">Rafter also uses her knowledge of ASL to engage with the Deaf community. Through the Engaged Scholars Program, Rafter is working with the Rhode Island School for the Deaf to set up a drama club and “contextualize acting training in a deafness perspective,” she said. She has also done an independent study on the intersections between deafness with queerness and theatre.</p>
<p class="p2">While some, like Rafter and Fieldsteel, incorporate ASL into their career plans, other students in the program study the language alongside other pursuits.</p>
<p class="p2">“What brings me such immense joy and gives me so much hope is to see so many people taking ASL and the variety of concentrations” represented in the classes, Rafter said. By bringing their knowledge of ASL to various fields, these students increase accessibility for Deaf people, she added.</p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">Liliana Luna-Nelson ’17 MD ’21 and Jeannette Gonzales Wright ’16 MD ’20, who created a medical elective entitled BIOL 6698: “Vital Signs: Introduction to Deaf Culture and American Sign Language for Medical Students” as undergraduate Program in Liberal Medical Education students in the ASL program, encourage the application of ASL to fields beyond Deaf studies. The elective consists of 10 two-hour-long classes, with Riker teaching a signing component in the first hour and a guest speaker leading the second hour. </span></p>
<p class="p2">The topics of the guest speakers, most of whom are Deaf, range from “mental health in the population to early hearing and detection intervention programs in Rhode Island to critiquing existing research that calls for certain communication methods over others,” Gonzales Wright said. Students learn how to sign to ask for preferred communication methods, medication administration routes and specific symptoms like chest pain and shortness of breath.</p>
<p class="p2">“Sometimes interpreters aren’t available, and if no one signs at all, a doctor should at the very least be able to get them to the emergency room,” Luna-Nelson said. “We need to show the medical community how important language access is, and give them the tools to talk to Deaf patients.”</p>
<p class="p2">The student-run Sign Languages Society is also working to interact more with the Deaf community beyond Brown. The Society works in tandem with the ASL program and other departments to host multiple public events throughout the year, such as a Deaf poet reading with the literary arts department and a speaker who is an advocate for inclusion of Deaf service members in the military, said Nicole Bencie ’19, a leader of the Sign Languages Society.</p>
<p class="p2">Nearly all sources said that with the high demand for ASL at the University, the program could benefit from various forms of expansion, such as more collaboration with other departments, more faculty and perhaps even an ASL concentration.</p>
<p class="p2">“My dream would be for Brown to have three, four, five professors so that they can specialize in different areas of the language or culture; for example, Deaf literature or Deaf history,” said Anne Prusky ’18, an alum of the ASL program at Brown.</p>
<p class="p2">Currently, the University has the second oldest and second largest ASL program among peer institutions, following Penn, Riker said. Harvard and Yale are just starting their programs, while Cornell has proposed beginning a program, he added.</p>
<p class="p2">“Right now, Brown is at the critical point where additional investment and resources are needed to push it to a new level, to make sure that we can offer a full four-year program, to be able to have a concentration,” Riker said. “In order to be able to have a robust program … we really need to have a multidisciplinary program.”</p>
<p class="p2">Bencie said that the ASL program is one of the reasons she chose to attend the University.</p>
<p class="p2">“It’s just not considered a foreign language in a lot of institutions of higher education,” she said. “That’s why Tim is so wonderful — he’s really made sure it’s seen as a language and not just as a tool or something to teach Deaf people.”</p>
<p class="p2">She added that the ASL community has become integral to her time at Brown. Students quickly become engaged in this vibrant and intimate culture,<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>she said.</p>
<p class="p2">Learning more about sign languages and the Deaf community is critical given that Deaf people have been historically viewed as inferior and unable to learn, think or reason, which is particularly evident in philosophy and academia, Riker said.</p>
<p class="p2">“The more we learn about Deaf people and sign languages, the more we understand what Deaf people have contributed to the world, and what the world can gain from having Deaf people as a part of their diversity,” Riker said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2833178</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-01-24 00:03:16]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-01-24 05:03:16]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[u-program-teaches-asl-deaf-culture-history]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-miapattillo"><![CDATA[miapattillo]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="american-sign-language"><![CDATA[American Sign Language]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="courses"><![CDATA[courses]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="deaf"><![CDATA[Deaf]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="features"><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="language"><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2374]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_spost_short_title]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_is_featured]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_embed_code]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[bdh_reporter_type]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Contributing Writer ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2833193]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kia_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[American Sign Language one of top 10 languages taught at University, continuing to grow]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[As students in the University’s American Sign Language program enter their classroom, they immediately fall silent. The mode of communication shifts from vocal chords and shaped lips to hand gestures and emotive expressions.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[custom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[single-feature-photo.php]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dsq_thread_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7185809931]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
