<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.9.9" created="2019-02-18 22:43" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Brown Daily Herald</title>
	<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com</link>
	<description>Serving the community daily since 1891</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 22:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://www.browndailyherald.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://www.browndailyherald.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2374</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[annakramer]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[anna@kramer.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Anna Kramer]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Anna]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Kramer]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2307</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[isabelgensler]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[i@g.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Isabel Gensler]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Isabel]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Gensler]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2456</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[emilydavies]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[emilydavies@comcast.net]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Emily Davies]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Emily]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Davies]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2610</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[Marlis Flinn]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[marlis@flinn.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Marlis Flinn]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Marlis]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Flinn]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

	<wp:category>
		<wp:term_id>2579</wp:term_id>
		<wp:category_nicename><![CDATA[graphics]]></wp:category_nicename>
		<wp:category_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:category_parent>
		<wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Graphics]]></wp:cat_name>
	</wp:category>

	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>http://www.browndailyherald.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/cropped-12371152_10153412077540958_8076506182949228397_o-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Brown Daily Herald</title>
	<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 

	<item>
		<title>Corporation grants Paxson second five-year term</title>
		<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com/2017/02/03/corporation-grants-president-paxson-second-five-year-term/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 05:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annakramer]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.browndailyherald.com/?p=2824532</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">The Corporation, the University’s highest governing body, granted President Christina Paxson P’19<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>a second five-year term Thursday, extending her tenure to 2021.</p>
<p class="p2">“The support for President Paxson was unanimous — there was never a thought of not renewing (her) contract,” said Chancellor Samuel Mencoff ’78 P’11 P’15.</p>
<p class="p2">In reaching their decision, Corporation members spoke to 59 people, including current Corporation members, several of the academic deans and a number of faculty and staff members, Mencoff said. The appointment, oversight, evaluation and reappointment of Paxson is one of the Corporation’s most important roles outlined in the University’s charter, Mencoff added.</p>
<p class="p2">Mencoff did not disclose how Paxson’s compensation as president may change during her second term, but as of 2014, her salary was $700,000 annually, according to the University’s 2014 tax returns. The Corporation hired an outside compensation consultant to ensure that president’s salary is competitive with peer institutions, Mencoff said.</p>
<p class="p2">Looking to the next five years: “We have a lot of work to do as a community, and I’m excited to have the honor and the opportunity to keep pushing forward,” Paxson said. “We have so much momentum right now.”</p>
<p class="p2">Paxson emphasized that she will prioritize undergraduate financial aid in her next term, for both low- and middle-income students.</p>
<p class="p2">“Honestly, we started off behind our peers, and we’ve fully caught up,” Paxson said in regards to financial aid. But she acknowledged the University must continue to make strides to fully address financial aid for low-income students. She did not commit to guaranteeing need-blind financial aid for international students, as this does not currently fit within the University’s financial ability, she said. Still, the University has increased the amount of financial aid for international students in recent years.</p>
<p class="p2">Alongside increasing financial aid, Paxson will also work to construct a new performing arts center, fundraise for 120 new endowed faculty chairs and pursue many of the goals outlined in the Diversity and Inclusion Action Plan, which she said has become a national model for similar plans at other universities.</p>
<p class="p2">“Plans like this can sometimes lose momentum,” she said. But the DIAP will remain a central University focus in her next term, she added.</p>
<p class="p2">Beyond her administrative roles, Paxson will continue to strengthen her relationship with the University community over the next five years. “It takes time to get to know students,” Paxson said, highlighting the difficulty in effectively communicating with a community of 9,000 people.</p>
<p class="p2">“I think she’s done a remarkably good job in setting a tone for the University and making people feel welcome,” said Professor Emeritus of Engineering Barrett Hazeltine. “It’s tough being president of Brown because we’re competing with schools with much larger endowments,” he added. Hazeltine is impressed with Paxson’s focus on undergraduate and graduate education and her involvement in the community, he said.</p>
<p class="p2">Student favor toward Paxson has positively shifted since she began her tenure. The percentage of students who strongly or somewhat disapprove of how Paxson is handling her administration decreased from about 25 percent in Spring 2015 to around 10 percent in Fall 2016, according to Herald polling data.</p>
<p class="p2">“I don’t know why approval ratings change that much over time … I don’t really worry about (it) that much,” Paxson said. She added that the administration may not always agree with students, but it supports them.</p>
<p class="p2">Some students have voiced concerns about Paxson’s growth of graduate programs in the past, but she defended their role as invaluable to the University. “I don’t see undergraduate and graduate education as being at odds with each other. It is not a zero-sum game if you do it right,” she said.</p>
<p class="p2">Cameron Johnson ’17, a member of the Brown University Community Council, said he hopes that in Paxson’s next term, the University will “boldly (lead) the stand against all threats to freedom and humanity.” The most successful moments of Paxson’s first term involved collaboration with students, he added. Whether the University continues this practice will determine the success of her next term, he said.</p>
<p class="p2">“The country is very divided,” Paxson said, addressing her role as president during the new Trump administration. “I haven’t seen divisions on issues of race, class and gender … like this in my lifetime,” she added.</p>
<p class="p2">The University will have to forcefully articulate its values in the coming years, Paxson said. She highlighted concerns about federal research funding for environmental issues and women’s reproductive health.</p>
<p class="p2">“President Paxson is the voice of Brown University to the outside world,” Mencoff said, adding that he places his full faith in her leadership in handling conflicts that may arise.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2824532</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-02-03 00:04:16]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-02-03 05:04:16]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[corporation-grants-president-paxson-second-five-year-term]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-annakramer"><![CDATA[annakramer]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="christina-paxson-2"><![CDATA[Christina Paxson]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="graphics"><![CDATA[Graphics]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="multimedia"><![CDATA[Multimedia]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="president-christina-paxson"><![CDATA[President Christina Paxson]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="top-stories"><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="university-hall"><![CDATA[University Hall]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="university-news"><![CDATA[University News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1919]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2824533]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_spost_short_title]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[bdh_reporter_type]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Senior Staff Writer ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_is_featured]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_embed_code]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kia_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Paxson voices support for undergraduate financial aid expansion, new performing arts center]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The Corporation, the University’s highest governing body, granted President Paxson P’19 a second five-year term Thursday, extending her tenure to 2021.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dsq_thread_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5517455588]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[custom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[single-feature-photo.php]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Gov. Raimondo proposes two years of free tuition at state colleges</title>
		<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com/2017/02/06/gov-raimondo-proposes-two-years-free-tuition-state-colleges/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 03:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[isabelgensler]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.browndailyherald.com/?p=2824605</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Gov. Gina Raimondo introduced the Rhode Island’s Promise proposal — which guarantees two years of free college for the state’s students if they choose to attend the Community College of Rhode Island, the University of Rhode Island or Rhode Island College — as a part of her FY2018 budget proposal in a press release Jan. 16.</p>
<p class="p2">“The data shows that in today’s economy, a college degree is the ticket to the middle class,” wrote Deputy Press Secretary Catherine Rolfe in an email to The Herald. “Roughly 70 percent of the jobs we’ll create in the coming years require at least an associate degree,” Rolfe wrote. But less than 45 percent of people in the state have received any higher education degree, according to data from the R.I. Department of Labor and Training.</p>
<p class="p2">“Low-income students spend nearly 75 percent of their family’s income to cover the cost of college,” according to a press release from the governor’s office. Almost 75 percent of R.I. students take on debt to earn a degree, and average debt adds to more than $35,000 after graduation — the second highest reported in the country.</p>
<p class="p2">The cost of the R.I.’s Promise proposal would be $30 million, which constitutes less than 0.5 percent of the state’s budget according to the R.I.’s Promise proposal website. All high school seniors who graduate from public, private or home school or get a GED, starting with the class of 2017, are eligible according to Raimondo’s proposal.</p>
<p class="p2">“(The governor’s) proposal to provide tuition and fees helps make college affordability more of a reality (and) would help ultimately reduce student debt levels and … increase completion rates,” said Andrew Bramson, president and CEO of The College Crusade of Rhode Island. “More state money to support higher education scholarships is really both needed and overdue,” he added.</p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">“When you put out a proposal like free tuition, it’s clearly going to catch the attention of first-generation and low-income families and students,” Bramson said. He added that College Crusade expects more students to pursue four-year over two-year institutions, considering that tuition over four years will now be cut in half. </span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">How Raimondo’s proposal contributes to completion “is more of an open question,” Bramson said. The proposal does not cover living expenses, which Bramson said “is what’s really determining whether or not low-income and first-generation students can finish college.”</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">The cost of tuition is not the only barrier preventing high school students from continuing on to college, said John Friedman, professor of economics and international and public affairs. “There’s evidence that small barriers to applying or applying for financial aid have really important effects in keeping kids out of college” he added. </span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">In addition to the R.I.’s Promise proposal, the governor has implemented several measures to lower the costs of attending college, including making the PSAT and SAT free for every tenth and eleventh grade student, as well as introducing the Open Textbook Initiative, which lowers the cost of textbooks, Rolfe wrote.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">Though there are several barriers to attending higher education, programs that “cut cost for attendance at these colleges do seem to have an effect on increasing college attendance rates,” Friedman said. “If you knock the price of attendance down by $1,000,” it increases enrollment in colleges by four to five percent, he added. Friedman also noted that though community college in Rhode Island is not very expensive after federal grants, tax credits and other loans, having a policy that guarantees free tuition greatly simplifies the process.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">The governor expects that once fully enacted, enrollment at URI, RIC and CCRI could increase by as much as 20 percent, Rolfe wrote. More than 7,000 students per year would be affected, she added.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">But the fact that the policy will only allow enrollment at state colleges may be a drawback. “Anytime you’re restricting peoples’ choices, that tends to not lead to better outcomes,” Friedman said.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">Friedman referenced one side effect of a similar policy in Massachusetts, where students who performed well enough on high school graduation exams were offered free tuition to the University of Massachusetts. The impact was that students who would have attended other institutions, typically private schools, instead went to UMass, which “led to a lower graduation rate because … kids don’t graduate from UMass at as high a rate as they graduate from other schools,” Friedman said.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s1">A tax credit for prospective R.I. college students that would make attending CCRI free but still leave open the option to go to other institutions would be a better option, he said.</span></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2824605</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-02-06 22:01:56]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-02-07 03:01:56]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[gov-raimondo-proposes-two-years-free-tuition-state-colleges]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-isabelgensler"><![CDATA[isabelgensler]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="college"><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="graphics"><![CDATA[Graphics]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="metro"><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="raimondo"><![CDATA[raimondo]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="top-stories"><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tuition"><![CDATA[tuition]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2227]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2824606]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_spost_short_title]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2578]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_is_featured]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_embed_code]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[bdh_reporter_type]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Senior Staff Writer]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kia_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Plan to cost around $30 million, aims to increase CCRI, URI, RIC enrollment by 20 percent]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_metadesc]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Gov. Gina Raimondo introduced the Rhode Island’s Promise proposal as a part of her FY2018 budget proposal in a press release Jan. 16.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dsq_thread_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5528915616]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[custom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[single-feature-photo.php]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Spring 2018 Herald poll results</title>
		<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com/2018/04/08/spring-2018-herald-poll-results/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 03:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[emilydavies]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.browndailyherald.com/?p=2830277</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Spring 2018 poll results can be found <a href="http://datascience.heraldweb.org/projects/spring2018poll/html/matrix.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>Do you approve or disapprove of the way Christina Paxson is handling her job as president of the University?</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">19.8% Strongly approve</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">39.6% Somewhat approve</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">6.0% Somewhat disapprove</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">0.2% Strongly Disapprove</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">34.4% No opinion</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>Do you approve or disapprove of the way the Undergraduate Council of Students is handling its job representing and addressing the concerns of the undergraduate student body?</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">10.2% Strongly approve</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">25.1% Somewhat approve</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">3.7% Somewhat disapprove</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">0.9% Strongly disapprove</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">60.2% No opinion</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>How strongly do you agree with the following: I feel like my concentration is respected by the Brown community.</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">54.8% Strongly agree</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">35.2% Somewhat agree</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">8.4% Somewhat disagree</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">1.5% Strongly disagree</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>Which of the following are you planning to apply to or attend?</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">13.4% Law school</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">27.1% Medical school</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">0.7% Veterinarian school</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">13.4% Business school</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">29.7% Academic PhD or Masters program</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">3.9% Other</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">12.1% None, I am not on a pre-professional track</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>How strongly do you agree with the following: I am confident in how my body looks.</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">24.8% Strongly agree</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">51.9% Somewhat agree</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">17.8% Somewhat disagree</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">5.6% Strongly disagree</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>How often do you take food from Brown eateries without paying (Josiah’s, Andrews, Blue Room, Campus Market, Ivy Room, library cafes)?</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">6.0% Daily</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">6.8% Two to three times a week</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">6.6% Once a week</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">14.9% Once or Twice a month</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">65.7% Never</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>How comfortable would you be approaching the Title IX office in response to an incident of sexual assault/violence/harassment?</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">23.2% Very comfortable</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">39.7% Somewhat comfortable</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">18.3% Somewhat uncomfortable</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">1.8% Very uncomfortable</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">17.0% No opinion</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>Have you ever felt you’ve had an inappropriate or uncomfortable sexual or romantic encounter with your professor or teaching assistant?</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">3.1% Yes</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">96.9% No</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>How often do you call a member of your family?</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">22.2% At least once per day</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">59.5% At least once per week</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">15.0% At least once per month</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">2.6% Less than once per month</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">0.6% Less than once per semester</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s3"><b>For which, if any, of the following conditions have you been prescribed medication in the past five years? (Circle all that apply)</b></span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">16.6% Anxiety</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">3.0% Attention deficit disorder</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">2.4% Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">1.1% Bipolar disorder</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">13.3% Depression</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">2.7% Obsessive-Compulsive disorder</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">0.1% Schizophrenia</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">2.8% Another mental health condition</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">76.7% None of the above</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">The poll was conducted over the course of three days — March 14-16. The margin of error is 3.4 percent with 95 percent confidence. The margins of error for specific subsets are as follows: 4.0 percent for females, 4.7 percent for males, 5.0 percent for first-years, 5.6 percent for sophomores, 6.9 percent for juniors, 7.1 percent for seniors, 4.5 percent for students who receive financial aid and 4.1 percent for students who do not receive financial aid.</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">The sample of students who took the poll is demographically similar to the undergraduate student body. The sample was 41.6 percent male and 56.8 percent female. First-years made up 33.6 percent, sophomores 28.3 percent, juniors 19.4 percent and seniors 18.7 percent of the poll. Of students represented in the poll, 5 percent receive just loans, 17.8 percent receive grants and loans, 15.8 percent receive grants covering some costs, 6.5 percent receive grants covering all costs and 54.9 percent receive no financial aid. Varsity athletes made up 9.9 percent, while non-athletes made up 90.1 percent of the sample. Of students surveyed, 79.4 percent identify as heterosexual, 4.5 percent as gay, 11 percent as bisexual and 5.1 percent as other. Those involved in a greek life organization made up 15.9 percent, while non-greek affiliated made up 84.1 percent.</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">Of students surveyed, 57.2 percent identify as white, 32.5 percent as Asian, 10.9 percent as Hispanic, 7.2 percent as black, 2 percent as American Indian/Alaska Native, 0.8 percent as Native Hawaiian/Pacific Islander and 2.9 percent as other. Students also marked their concentration area(s) — 31.7 percent are in the humanities/arts, 23.2 percent in life sciences, 32.2 percent in physical sciences, 12.5 percent in business (BEO or econ) and 20.2 percent in social sciences. Of students polled, 13.5 percent are legacy students, meaning they have a parent, grandparent or sibling who attended Brown, and 86.4 percent are not. First-generation students made up 16.4 percent of students surveyed and non-first-generation students made up 83.6 percent of the sample. Statistical significance was established at the 0.05 level. All cross tabulations are statistically significant.</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">University News Editor Anna Kramer ’20 and Metro Editor Emily Davies ’19.5 coordinated the poll. Herald section editors, senior staff writers and other staff members conducted the poll.</span></p>
<p class="p6"><span class="s3">Over the next several weeks, The Herald will publish a series of articles about individual poll questions. Find results of previous polls at <a href="http://thebdh.org/poll">thebdh.org/poll</a>.</span></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2830277</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-04-08 23:05:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-04-09 03:05:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[spring-2018-herald-poll-results]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-emilydavies"><![CDATA[emilydavies]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-annakramer"><![CDATA[annakramer]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="body-image"><![CDATA[body image]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="calling-home"><![CDATA[calling home]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="graphics"><![CDATA[Graphics]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="medication"><![CDATA[medication]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="multimedia"><![CDATA[Multimedia]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="spring-2018-poll"><![CDATA[Spring 2018 poll]]></category>
		<category domain="series" nicename="spring-2018-poll"><![CDATA[Spring 2018 Poll]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2203]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_spost_short_title]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2579]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_is_featured]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_embed_code]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[bdh_reporter_type]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Metro Editor and University News Editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2830311]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2018-04-09]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dsq_thread_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[6603013921]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_slug]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[draft-davies-kramer-poll-data]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[kia_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Among other findings, 34.3 percent of students report stealing from U. dining halls, eateries]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[custom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[single-feature-photo.php]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_series_part_5237]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Election day, by the numbers</title>
		<link>http://www.browndailyherald.com/2018/11/04/election-day-numbers/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 04:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marlis Flinn]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.browndailyherald.com/?p=2832382</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[[gallery size="large" ids="2832390,2832395,2832388"]]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2832382</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2018-11-04 23:48:51]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2018-11-05 04:48:51]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[election-day-numbers]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-marlis-flinn"><![CDATA[Marlis Flinn]]></category>
		<category domain="author" nicename="cap-andrewfriberg"><![CDATA[andrewfriberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="2018-midterm-elections"><![CDATA[2018 midterm elections]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="2018-midterms"><![CDATA[2018 Midterms]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="graphics"><![CDATA[Graphics]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="metro"><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="national-politics"><![CDATA[National politics]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="politics"><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2174]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_spost_short_title]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_primary_category]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2578]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_content_score]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[30]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_is_featured]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[wpzoom_post_embed_code]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[custom_post_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[single-gallery.php]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dsq_thread_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7020318047]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
